Stop taking creatine monohydrate right now.
In this video, I want to talk about the incredible dangers and also the chances
that you are just wasting your money on top of that.
I will talk about everything, the most common mistakes,
which chances are most likely you are doing these mistakes.
And I will reveal in the end of the video, the scientifically proven best protocol
to take creatine monohydrate, because yes, it is amazing.
Yes, it has incredible benefits proven by hundreds of studies.
It is literally, as you probably already heard, the most researched and most
beneficial supplement, not just for muscle, for cognitive functions,
for many more things, which I want to reveal in the video.
But I want to start with the most common mistakes, either dangerous mistakes
or you just wasting your money, not getting the benefits before I dive deep
into the most beneficial and best protocol to follow.
Easy to follow steps in the end of the video.
So let's go straight into it.
Today, we are diving deep into the creatine monohydrate myths
and, more importantly, into the most common mistakes.
Because if I am asking the people in the gym, just right there,
like many people are really just taking it wrong.
And the right way of taking it proves a lot of crazy benefits,
backed by hundreds of randomized control, human trials and brand new meta analysis.
Yes, some benefits are, for example, it regenerates ATP.
So you push harder, you lift heavier and recover faster.
In fact, I am myself plateauing out here with working out on a natural way.
And then creatine is amazing.
It gives you this additional 10 percent.
You're lifting harder, you're getting more muscle.
Of course, you are getting more volume also.
It is completely amazing.
It's really one of my favorite supplements, right?
And I am not taking it currently, but I will start taking it soon again
because I am definitely plateauing out here.
And again, cognitive benefits, I want to take them.
But recent 2025 meta analysis show also clear boost in upper and lower body strength and power.
It pulls water into the muscle cells, right?
Some people think, oh, yeah, you're just pulling water,
but it's not going below the skin.
It's going straight into the muscle, which is a good thing.
But there is some dangers attached to it.
And I want to talk about it.
If you know about it, there are no dangers.
It pulls water into the muscle cells for that very full pumped look,
which is, of course, amazing.
While driving real growth, new trials also prove cognitive wins,
as I already teased that before.
I want to talk about most common mistakes people are doing
and then about the best protocol to follow.
So stick here with me.
But first of all, some more of the benefits
because I really want to get you hooked on that supplement.
It's amazing.
I'm not even selling it.
No links, nothing, but it is amazing.
You get better memory, faster processing, sharper focus, especially very strong for women.
Sometimes women think, oh, no, that's not for me.
I don't want to get big muscle.
Come on, guys, BS, right?
You don't have enough testosterone to build these huge muscles.
Even for elderly women, elderly men, it's amazing, right?
Especially, as I said, very, very good for women,
older adults, vegetarians, if you're watching it, vegans, you need to take it.
It's amazing.
If you are short on sleep or stress taking a higher dose of creatine monohydrate
can restore your cognitive function for the whole day.
It's really amazing.
And everyone, like a big part of you watching will probably still ask, oh, is it safe?
Well, usually, yes.
A massive 2025 analysis over 680 clinical trials combined
found zero extra side effects versus the placebo group, including the kidney markers.
The slight rise in creatinine is very normal, metabolic turnover, not damage.
And in fact, better markers for kidney health are Cystitine C, GFR, you know,
like potassium sodium ratios, like all of these things are much, much more beneficial
to check for kidney health than just the creatinine ratio.
Especially if you are having a lot of muscle mass, it might be elevated anyways, right?
Here's why the title says, do not take creatine monohydrate before watching this
or like danger, creatine, danger.
I don't know what I will choose as a title, but most people make critical mistakes
that cause bloating, cramps, stomach issues, zero results or unnecessary worry.
Some common mistakes include loading too aggressively and getting diarrhea or painful bloating,
using fancy, expensive forms with additives.
When playing creatine monohydrate, I use the German one, Crea Pure,
which is the best in my opinion, but just use whatever you feel like, wins every single study, right?
And then this is a very important one, which could be connected to some minor danger, right?
Especially long term, not drinking enough water.
So water retention looks puffy instead of full.
And also, if you are drawing water into the muscle, you are not urinating that water out.
So when you take creatine, 5 grams, 10 grams or more, should be at least 5,
but I will come to the protocol, you should drink more water to compensate for some of the water,
which goes into the muscle, right?
So I usually drink 7, 8 liters because I sweat so much, but a normal person drinks like 3 liters.
Well, if you take creatine monohydrates, you just drink a little bit more.
You always drink enough so your urine is pale yellow and you are urinating at least 6 times a day.
That is a nice rule of thumb, I would say, right?
So then also taking inconsistent doses or skipping rest days,
believing the kidney myth is instead of like the 2025 data is also a big mistake, right?
So just drink more and then it's fine if your kidneys are healthy.
Taking it on an empty stomach can also be a mistake, of course, not for everyone.
Some people are completely fine with it.
It is quite well absorbed, quite well tolerated,
but if you're not taking it on an empty stomach, it is for everyone, usually much easier to handle.
Or also another big mistake is expecting magic without heart training and solid nutrition.
You need solid nutrition first, you need proper sleep first, you need your rest days
and you need the training and then you get the benefits, right?
These errors are why so many people quit or think creatine just doesn't work.
BS, it's the best working supplement in the world, right?
So what's the exact protocol that unlocks the full muscles, strength and brain benefits without the side effects?
Well, here it is. Use only high quality creatine monohydrate.
I would prefer creatine pure from Germany.
For faster saturation, do an optional loading phase.
20 grams per day split into four or five gram doses, for example, for the first seven days.
And then you can drop to a simple maintenance dose of five grams every single day
with proper diet that should be enough for muscle gain.
If you want additional cognitive benefits, some people are swearing by 10 grams and more every single day,
but 20 grams then going down to five to eight grams for muscle growth and muscle preservation should be the way to go, right?
Take it anytime that fits your schedule.
This is the most important because skipping out is usually when you miss out.
So just do what works for your consistency, beats the perfect timing,
mix it with a meal or a shake containing carbs or protein for slightly better uptake.
Drink plenty of extra water daily.
As I already said, if you take it, you have to drink some more extra water, which is fine, right?
I mean, who cares about drinking a little bit more water?
Keep taking it on rest days too.
This is very important.
Follow this and you will finally get every proven benefit in the world.
Science backs this up.
Let me know what you think about that.
Make sure you're smashing the like button to a new all-time high
and watch this very important video about workouts that as always, guys, as always, bye, bye.