I knew with two pretty good blows to the back of the head that it didn't release, that I
was probably going to have to do something a little more drastic.
About a quarter mile into that run, I ended up hearing some pine needle
rustle, like a stick break, and I turned around and just was pretty bummed out
to see an outline chasing after me.
It just kind of kept running and lunged at me.
It was going toward my face, so I threw up my hands to kind of block my face.
At which point, it grabbed onto my hand and wrist,
and from there, it started to claw at my face and neck,
and that's when kind of my fear response turned into more of a fight response.
There was a point where I was concerned that I wasn't going to make it out of it,
and I think it might have been a mix of me tussling with the cat and it's so clawing at me,
and then thinking about another cat potentially coming along.
It got a claw on my lip, and I tried to throw it off me at that point,
and then you took a little tumble down the south side of the trail,
and down there just kind of had a little wrestling match at which point I was able to get on top of it,
pin its back legs, so it didn't get any soft tissue scratched out in my other regions.
I was grabbing around for sticks.
I only had my left hand free, my right hand was still walking its jaws.
I tried to get out of its neck to see if I could stab it in the neck to get it to release.
That wasn't working the sticks were breaking, so then I picked up a rock that I had seen kind of near us.
It was pretty heavy, it was kind of hard to reel,
and I tried to give it a few bashes in the back of the head,
but unfortunately I just kind of had tough times swinging it with my arms still locked into the cat's jaws.
I stepped on it on its neck with my right foot,
and just slowly after a few minutes I thought it would be getting close,
and then it started thrashing again and had a few more scratches that resulted from those thrashes at that point.
And I'd say another couple minutes later it finally stopped moving and then jaws opened,
and I was able to kind of scramble back up the hill and get the heck out of dodge.
And I guess in my mind I replayed it. It seems like a long time, but I've been thinking 10 minutes at most.
He did all the right things, he put his hands up and yelled at it, and it still came after him.